<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<infotexts language="English" nowhitespace="false" translatedname="English">
  <!-- Multitools -->
  
  <!-- removed: duplicate functionality of EK armory (even though i did it first!!) >:( -->
  <entityname.thal_headsetchannel>Multichannel Headset</entityname.thal_headsetchannel>
  <entitydescription.thal_headsetchannel>Channeled Headset. Enter a number to change the channel.</entitydescription.thal_headsetchannel>
  
  <entityname.thal_rainbowsprayer>TruColor Sprayer</entityname.thal_rainbowsprayer>
  <entitydescription.thal_rainbowsprayer>An modified sprayer engineered for painting with a more vibrant color set. Enter colors in the format Red,Green,Blue,Transparency (ranging from 0 to 255). Requires TruPaint, fabricated from other paints.</entitydescription.thal_rainbowsprayer>
  
  <entityname.thal_sign>Sign</entityname.thal_sign>
  <entitydescription.thal_sign>A standard white sign for displaying text. Can be attatched to a wall and written on with a pen. Water resistant, but flammable.</entitydescription.thal_sign>
  <ItemMsgWriteSelectPen>[[select]] Write (Pen)</ItemMsgWriteSelectPen>
  <ItemMsgDetatchUsePen>[[use]] Detatch (Pen)</ItemMsgDetatchUsePen>
  
  <!-- removed: overpowered. dislike items that make others obsolete regardless of price. -->
  <entityname.thal_multitool>Navy Grade Pocketknife</entityname.thal_multitool>
  <entitydescription.thal_multitool>A mass produced pocketknife issued to many ships by the coalition but used by everyone. Comes with retractable tools mimicking a screwdriver, wrench, and comes with a foldable blade designed with minor alien combat in mind.</entitydescription.thal_multitool>
  <!-- Handheld Maps -->
  <entityname.thal_map>Automap</entityname.thal_map>
  <entitydescription.thal_map>Generic Automap that scans the hull to detect the ship layout as well as any abnormalities in the shell. Useful as a map and easy on the battery.</entitydescription.thal_map>
  
  <entityname.thal_mapwater>Hydromap</entityname.thal_mapwater>
  <entitydescription.thal_mapwater>Specially designed Automap designed to not only scan the hull of the ship and the according breaches, but also the water within the ship. Created for use among Mechanics, but good for anyone looking to patch and drain a ship.</entitydescription.thal_mapwater>
  
  <entityname.thal_mapair>Aeromap</entityname.thal_mapair>
  <entitydescription.thal_mapair>Specially designed Automap designed not only to scan the hull of the ship and breaches, but also the oxygen levels within the ship. Created for use among Engineers, but good for anyone looking to detect electrical fires or general oxygen absence.</entitydescription.thal_mapair>
  
  <entityname.thal_mapall>Omnimap</entityname.thal_mapall>
  <entitydescription.thal_mapall>Advanced Automap engineered to scan for the hull, breaches, water, and oxygen levels. Its all-seeing nature consumes battery faster than usual.</entitydescription.thal_mapall>
  
  <entityname.thal_foldingchair>Folding Chair</entityname.thal_foldingchair>
  <entitydescription.thal_foldingchair>A steel folding chair that can be moved, sat on, or swung wrestling-style.</entitydescription.thal_foldingchair>
  <ItemMsgSitDownSelect>[[select]] Sit Down</ItemMsgSitDownSelect>
  <ItemMsgPickUpAction>[[use]] Pick Up</ItemMsgPickUpAction>
  
  <entityname.thal_foldingtable>Folding Table</entityname.thal_foldingtable>
  <entitydescription.thal_foldingtable>A steel folding table that can be picked up and moved. Players can also drop items on it.</entitydescription.thal_foldingtable>
  
  <entityname.thal_dpbm>Dave's Phat Beat Machine</entityname.thal_dpbm>
  <entitydescription.thal_dpbm>A machine that plays and layers instrumental loops. Press a button and wait no more than 9 seconds. Each loop is 9 seconds long.</entitydescription.thal_dpbm>
  
  <entityname.thal_shockmodule>Discharge Module</entityname.thal_shockmodule>
  <entitydescription.thal_shockmodule>Wireable module that can be hooked up to the wall like a button. On activation, will discharge a stunning bolt of electricity.</entitydescription.thal_shockmodule>
  
  <entityname.thal_pen>Pen</entityname.thal_pen>
  <entitydescription.thal_pen>A cheap waterproof plastic pen with an eraser on the back to rub off ink. Allows you to write on memos and signs, or stab people. Typically restricted to captains to prevent vandalism.</entitydescription.thal_pen>
  
  <entityname.thal_memo>Memo</entityname.thal_memo>
  <entitydescription.thal_memo>A small writeable note. Requires a pen to edit. The contents don't persist between rounds.</entitydescription.thal_memo>
  
  <entityname.thal_memoboard>Memo Board</entityname.thal_memoboard>
  <entitydescription.thal_memoboard>Board used for containing memos. Players can mouse over the notes to see what they say. As of Barotrauma 0.10.5.0+ notes unfortunately do not save their contents between rounds/sub editor.</entitydescription.thal_memoboard>
  
  <entityname.thal_breachcharge>Breaching Charge</entityname.thal_breachcharge>
  <entitydescription.thal_breachcharge>Shaped charge that specializes in shredding doors. Attatch it next to a door, set it, and run for cover. Ideal for ruins, wrecks, and weld-ins.</entitydescription.thal_breachcharge>
  <!-- Traitor tools -->
  
  <entityname.thal_hackeruplink>r3n3g8 Uplink</entityname.thal_hackeruplink>
  <entitydescription.thal_hackeruplink>A portable menu capable of spawning in items from the r3n3g8 catalogue, provided you have the materials.</entitydescription.thal_hackeruplink>
  
  <entityname.thal_powersink>Powersink</entityname.thal_powersink>
  <entitydescription.thal_powersink>r3n3g8 engineered attatchable module capable of putting a massive load on a power grid when wired in. Useful for electrical pump and dump attacks that will easily mass-fry junctions and occasionally start fires.</entitydescription.thal_powersink>
  
  
  <entityname.thal_structnanogrenade>Structure Repair Grenade</entityname.thal_structnanogrenade>
  <entitydescription.thal_structnanogrenade>A single-use burst grenade that employs nanobots to quickly repair large segments of hull. Ideal for emergencies where quick hull fixes are needed.</entitydescription.thal_structnanogrenade>
  
  
  <!-- unimplemented: unable to access itemcomponent scope via nearbyitems -->
  <entityname.thal_doorkey>Door Spoofer Key</entityname.thal_doorkey>
  <entitydescription.thal_doorkey>r3n3g8 engineered Near Field Communications tag designed to trick a door into opening without the wait of a crowbar. Only good for two uses, so be mindful of automatically closing doors.</entitydescription.thal_doorkey>
  
  <!-- unimplemented: unable to access itemcomponent scope via nearbyitems -->
  <entityname.thal_signaljammer>Signal Jammer</entityname.thal_signaljammer>
  <entitydescription.thal_signaljammer>r3n3g8 engineered shortwave frequency bombarder. Will easily prevent radio communication between crew. The disruption increases with proximity, though, so crew may be able to tell when they're nearby.</entitydescription.thal_signaljammer>
  
  <entityname.thal_partyblower>Party Blower</entityname.thal_partyblower>
  <entitydescription.thal_partyblower>Unrolls when blown. BA-DOO!</entitydescription.thal_partyblower>
  
  <entityname.thal_whoopeecushion>Whoopee Cushion</entityname.thal_whoopeecushion>
  <entitydescription.thal_whoopeecushion>A cushion that makes a loud, unflattering noise when squeezed. Can be used like a bike horn, or dropped on the floor where it can be stepped on.</entitydescription.thal_whoopeecushion>
  
  <entityname.thal_confettigrenade>Confetti Grenade</entityname.thal_confettigrenade>
  <entitydescription.thal_confettigrenade>Looks like a frag grenade but releases confetti. Good for fakeouts and general intimidation. Yay!</entitydescription.thal_confettigrenade>
  
  <entityname.thal_blindfold>Blindfold</entityname.thal_blindfold>
  <entitydescription.thal_blindfold>When worn, obstructs vision. Ineffective on bots.</entitydescription.thal_blindfold>
  
  <entityname.thal_chaoshorn>Chaos Horn</entityname.thal_chaoshorn>
  <entitydescription.thal_chaoshorn>Creates the sound of an explosion, minus the actual explosion. Limited uses, and may alert security. BANG!</entitydescription.thal_chaoshorn>
  
  <entityname.thal_muzzle>Muzzle</entityname.thal_muzzle>
  <entitydescription.thal_muzzle>When worn, prevents any kind of speech.</entitydescription.thal_muzzle>
  
  <entityname.thal_bananapeel>Banana Peel</entityname.thal_bananapeel>
  <entitydescription.thal_bananapeel>Slippery. When dropped or thrown, will slip the first thing that walks on it. Must be thrown again in order for more slipping to occur.</entitydescription.thal_bananapeel>
  
  <entityname.thal_waterballoon>Rubber Balloon</entityname.thal_waterballoon>
  <entitydescription.thal_waterballoon>A balloon that can be filled with water if the user is in water, and thrown. Can be turned into fantastical balloonsculpture by a Clown.</entitydescription.thal_waterballoon>
  
  <!-- decal baloons could be implemented now, but are really for the 0.11.X.X updates where decals are permenant -->
  
  <entityname.thal_paintballoon>Paint Balloon</entityname.thal_paintballoon>
  <entitydescription.thal_paintballoon>This throwable balloon has been filled with paint. On impact, it will certainly make a mess.</entitydescription.thal_paintballoon>
  
  <entityname.thal_bloodballoon>Blood Balloon</entityname.thal_bloodballoon>
  <entitydescription.thal_bloodballoon>This throwable balloon has been filled with blood. On impact, the residual mess will probably look like a crime scene.</entitydescription.thal_bloodballoon>
  
  <entityname.thal_jokerevolver>Joke Revolver</entityname.thal_jokerevolver>
  <entitydescription.thal_jokerevolver>A revolver that ejects a flag instead of firing bullets. Good for fakeouts and general intimidation.</entitydescription.thal_jokerevolver>
  
  <entityname.thal_bowlingball>Bowling Ball</entityname.thal_bowlingball>
  <entitydescription.thal_bowlingball>Bowl like you would throw a grenade. Great for knocking over pins and people.</entitydescription.thal_bowlingball>
  
  <entityname.thal_clownpack>Giggles von Honkington</entityname.thal_clownpack>
  <entitydescription.thal_clownpack>Stylish backpack with a funny face on it. Partially absorbs shocks and ballistics from behind, making running a good option.</entitydescription.thal_clownpack>
  
  <entityname.thal_candle>Candle</entityname.thal_candle>
  <entitydescription.thal_candle>Decorative light source that uses up wax as it burns. Light/Snuff it by aiming and pressing left click once. Extinguished by water.</entitydescription.thal_candle>
  
  <entityname.thal_ouijaboard>Ouija Board</entityname.thal_ouijaboard>
  <entitydescription.thal_ouijaboard>Occultism board for establishing communications with spirits via poltergism. Used in rituals.</entitydescription.thal_ouijaboard>
  
  <!-- Cooking tools -->
  
  <entityname.thal_carver>Meat Cleaver</entityname.thal_carver>
  <entitydescription.thal_carver>A meat cleaver that will turn carcasses into cookable meat when repeatedly hitting a dead body. Can also be used in cooking stations to slice whole muscles into neater cuts for steaks, porkchops, and other more manageable meat.</entitydescription.thal_carver>
  
  <entityname.thal_foodcart>Food Cart</entityname.thal_foodcart>
  <entitydescription.thal_foodcart>Portable Cooking Station. Can be used to prepare a variety of foods depending on what cookware its user has equipped.</entitydescription.thal_foodcart>
  
  <entityname.thal_meatgrinder>Meat Grinder</entityname.thal_meatgrinder>
  <entitydescription.thal_meatgrinder>A handheld meat grinder that can be used to process more manageable meats into ground meat.</entitydescription.thal_meatgrinder>
  
  <entityname.thal_meatgrinder>Boiling Pot</entityname.thal_meatgrinder>
  <entitydescription.thal_meatgrinder>A large pot capable of holding most food items. Capable of boiling whatever it contains, provided a cooking station.</entitydescription.thal_meatgrinder>
  
  <entityname.thal_shroomseed>Ramblin Evil Seed</entityname.thal_shroomseed>
  <entitydescription.thal_shroomseed>Odd smelling seed covered in spores, capable of being planted like any other. Will produce enough yeast shroom to make you rich, but may release spores.</entitydescription.thal_shroomseed>
  
  <entityname.thal_shroomcure>Anti-Mycelium</entityname.thal_shroomcure>
  <entitydescription.thal_shroomcure>Cures Mushroomization. Has a distinct viscosity not unlike Calyxanide.</entitydescription.thal_shroomcure>
  
  <entityname.thal_zombieseed>Pupa Seed</entityname.thal_zombieseed>
  <entitydescription.thal_zombieseed>A strange, cold seed. Will grow into a Pupa Stalk, which grows maggot hives that can be ruptured for saline. The maggots revive dead creatures so be careful!</entitydescription.thal_zombieseed>
  
  <entityname.thal_maggothive>Maggot Hive</entityname.thal_maggothive>
  <entitydescription.thal_maggothive>Ruptures into maggots if </entitydescription.thal_maggothive>
  
  <entityname.thal_rustseed>Rustwilt Seed</entityname.thal_rustseed>
  <entitydescription.thal_rustseed>Foul smelling seed that grows into a rustwilt plant. The plant produces opium, but also unleashes corrosive clouds that may burn through surrounding walls and drain oxygen. Somewhat high maintainence.</entitydescription.thal_rustseed>
  
  <entityname.thal_clownseed>Circusprig Seed</entityname.thal_clownseed>
  <entitydescription.thal_clownseed>Funny smelling seed that grows into a Circusprig plant. The plant grows somewhat unpredictable produce, and has the tendency to leak seltzer water.</entitydescription.thal_clownseed>
  
  <entityname.thal_wheatseed>Wheat Seed</entityname.thal_wheatseed>
  <entitydescription.thal_wheatseed>A wheat seed from Earth, genetically modified to grow more quickly in hydroponic conditions. Essential for making flour.</entitydescription.thal_wheatseed>
  
  <entityname.thal_wheatseed>Wheat Seed</entityname.thal_wheatseed>
  <entitydescription.thal_wheatseed>A wheat seed from Earth, genetically modified to grow more quickly in hydroponic conditions. Essential for making flour.</entitydescription.thal_wheatseed>
  
  <entityname.thal_wheat>Wheat</entityname.thal_wheat>
  <entitydescription.thal_wheat>A bundle of wheat.</entitydescription.thal_wheat>
  
  <entityname.thal_sugarcane>Sugarcane</entityname.thal_sugarcane>
  <entitydescription.thal_sugarcane>A slightly sweet tasting plant from earth, genetically modified to grow more quickly in hydroponic conditions. Unlike many plants, sugarcane grows from itself instead of seeds.</entitydescription.thal_sugarcane>
  
  <entityname.thal_botanistsuit>Hydroponics Cleansuit</entityname.thal_botanistsuit>
  <entitydescription.thal_botanistsuit>Lightweight suit designed for use handling volatile flora. Mildly resists burns and lacerations.</entitydescription.thal_botanistsuit>
  
  <entityname.thal_botanistmask>Aerosol Respirator</entityname.thal_botanistmask>
  <entitydescription.thal_botanistmask>Industrial grade mask with an air filtration system built in, primarily to resist the effects of toxic fumes from plants. Can be loaded with oxygen to behave like a diving mask.</entitydescription.thal_botanistmask>
  
  <entityname.thal_fumigator>Fumigator</entityname.thal_fumigator>
  <entitydescription.thal_fumigator>Modified flamer that discharges gasses from whatever gas cylinder is loaded into it.</entitydescription.thal_fumigator>
  
  <msggascylinderrequired>Gas Cylinder Required</msggascylinderrequired>
  
  <entityname.thal_assembler>Atomic Converter</entityname.thal_assembler>
  <entitydescription.thal_assembler>Handheld subatomic fabricator capable of assembling complex devices. Requires insertion of a Schematic and a material specified by the Schematics' description.</entitydescription.thal_assembler>
  
  <entityname.thal_constructor>Universal Constructor</entityname.thal_constructor>
  <entitydescription.thal_constructor>Attatchable fabricator with the potential to 3D print extremely complex machinery with quantum manipulation capabilities.</entitydescription.thal_constructor>
  
  <entityname.thal_recipeconstructor>Schematic: Universal Constructor</entityname.thal_recipeconstructor>
  <entitydescription.thal_recipeconstructor>Datachip containing fabrication instructions for the assembly of a Universal Constructor, a device capable of creating items allowing access to the upper echelons of science.
  Insert into: Atomic Assembler
  Alongside a: Titanium-Aluminum Bar</entitydescription.thal_recipeconstructor>
  
  <entityname.thal_recipeplanter>Schematic: Small Planter Box</entityname.thal_recipeplanter>
  <entitydescription.thal_recipeplanter>Datachip containing fabrication instructions for the assembly of a Universal Constructor, a device capable of creating items allowing access to the upper echelons of science.
  Insert into: Atomic Assembler
  Alongside a: Metal Crate</entitydescription.thal_recipeplanter>
  
  <entityname.thal_recipefumigator>Schematic: Fumigator</entityname.thal_recipefumigator>
  <entitydescription.thal_recipefumigator>Datachip containing fabrication instructions for the assembly of a Fumigator, a device capable of ejecting pressurized gasses.
  Insert into: Atomic Assembler
  Alongside a: Welding Tool</entitydescription.thal_recipefumigator>
  
  <entityname.thal_recipebotanistmask>Schematic: Respirator</entityname.thal_recipebotanistmask>
  <entitydescription.thal_recipebotanistmask>Datachip containing fabrication instructions for the assembly of an Aerosol Respirator, a device capable of filtering out toxic gasses.
  Insert into: Atomic Assembler
  Alongside a: Diving Mask</entitydescription.thal_recipebotanistmask>
  
  <entityname.thal_recipedischarger>Schematic: Discharger</entityname.thal_recipedischarger>
  <entitydescription.thal_recipedischarger>Datachip containing fabrication instructions for the assembly of a Discharger, a weak rechargeable pistol.
  Insert into: Atomic Assembler
  Alongside a: Handheld Sonar</entitydescription.thal_recipedischarger>
  
  <entityname.thal_recipefungicide>Schematic: Fungicide</entityname.thal_recipefungicide>
  <entitydescription.thal_recipefungicide>Datachip containing fabrication instructions for the assembly of an Aerosol Fungicide Cylinder, a pressurized fumigator cylinder for stopping mushroom outbreaks.
  Insert into: Atomic Assembler
  Alongside a: Ramblin Evil Seed</entitydescription.thal_recipefungicide>
  
  <entityname.thal_cylinderspore>Ramblin Spore Cylinder</entityname.thal_cylinderspore>
  <entitydescription.thal_cylinderspore>Pressurized gas cylinder containing particle spores for Ramblin Evil Mushrooms. Avoid dropping.</entitydescription.thal_cylinderspore>
  
  <entityname.thal_cylinderlaughing>Nitrous Oxide Cylinder</entityname.thal_cylinderlaughing>
  <entitydescription.thal_cylinderlaughing>Pressurized gas cylinder containing Nitrous Oxide, a commonplace gas with analgesic effects stemming from deprivation of oxygen to the brain. Avoid dropping.</entitydescription.thal_cylinderlaughing>
  
  <entityname.thal_cylindershroomcure>Aerosol Fungicide Cylinder</entityname.thal_cylindershroomcure>
  <entitydescription.thal_cylindershroomcure>Pressurezed gas cylinder containing vaporized Anti-Mycelium. Kills Ramblin Mushrooms and disinfect victims of mushroomization.</entitydescription.thal_cylindershroomcure>
  
  <entityname.thal_cylinderteargas>CS Gas Cylinder</entityname.thal_cylinderteargas>
  <entitydescription.thal_cylinderteargas>Pressurized gas cylinder containing 2-chlorobenzalmalononitrile modified to serve as an airborne irritant. If the gas makes contact with eyes it will result in temporary irritation and blindness. Useful for self defense.</entitydescription.thal_cylinderteargas>
  
  <entityname.thal_hydrophonicsign>Hydroponic Hazard Sign</entityname.thal_hydrophonicsign>
  <entitydescription.thal_hydrophonicsign>A sign that can be dropped on the floor or attatched to a wall in order to indicate an area of botanical hazard ranging from exploding pomegrenades to infectious spores.</entitydescription.thal_hydrophonicsign>
  
  <entityname.thal_botanistbook>Botanist's Almanac</entityname.thal_botanistbook>
  <entitydescription.thal_botanistbook>Book detailing the care of various crops and plants capable of being grown by the botanist.</entitydescription.thal_botanistbook>
  
  <entityname.thal_discourager>Static Discourager</entityname.thal_discourager>
  <entitydescription.thal_discourager>Self defense weapon that administers a controlled shock, which disrupts the nervous system. The lack of complete incapacitation makes it an ideal weapon for self defense.</entitydescription.thal_discourager>
  
    <entityname.thal_cultistbook>Abridged Necronomicon</entityname.thal_cultistbook>
  <entitydescription.thal_cultistbook>Book detailing the basics of the cultist role. Hold to read, type in the topmost bar to navigate.</entitydescription.thal_cultistbook>
  
  <entityname.thal_singularity>Gravitational Singularity"</entityname.thal_singularity>
  <entitydescription.thal_singularity>Horrific gravitational anamoly that grows the more characters are sucked into it.</entitydescription.thal_singularity>
  
  <entityname.thal_secondchance>Phoenix Injector</entityname.thal_secondchance>
  <entitydescription.thal_secondchance>A steroidal epinephrine solution rigged to automatically inject when in the hotbar of a critically injured person. Going critical with this in your hotbar revives you temporarily, allowing you to seek medical aide.</entitydescription.thal_secondchance>
  
  <entityname.thal_geneticinit>CRISPR-Cas9 Solution</entityname.thal_geneticinit>
  <entitydescription.thal_geneticinit>Syringe containing extracellular fluid that targets certain genes in DNA using CRISPR, and cleaves them using the Cas9 enzyme to induce genetic plasticity. After application, DNA grafts can be injected into patients for easy DNA splicing, but prolonged inaction could be disastrous. The longer the patient is in 'meltdown', the more unintended genetic oddities they may gain.</entitydescription.thal_geneticinit>
  
  <entityname.thal_geneticgraft>DNA Grafter</entityname.thal_geneticgraft>
  <entitydescription.thal_geneticgraft>Syringe which DNA samples can be inserted into. When injected into someone undergoing a CRISPR-Cas9 induced meltdown, this attatches the DNA to the cut sections, resulting in en vivo gene splicing.</entitydescription.thal_geneticgraft>
  
  <entityname.thal_dnascanner>DNA Scanner</entityname.thal_dnascanner>
  <entitydescription.thal_dnascanner>A DNA scanner that collects DNA from the saliva molecules of living beings. Will not work on dead creatures. Requires power, and must be wired correctly in order to be properly used.</entitydescription.thal_dnascanner>
  
  <entityname.thal_dnahuman>Human DNA</entityname.thal_dnahuman>
  <entitydescription.thal_dnahuman>Complete genetic sequence of the standard Homo Sapien. Can be used to develop anti-Humanoid technologies, or in DNA grafts for reverting humans back to normal. </entitydescription.thal_dnahuman>
  
  <entityname.thal_dnamudraptor>Mudraptor DNA</entityname.thal_dnamudraptor>
  <entitydescription.thal_dnamudraptor>Complete genetic sequence of the standard Europan Mudraptor. Can be used to develop anti-Mudraptor technologies, or in DNA grafts for gene splicing. </entitydescription.thal_dnamudraptor>
  
  <entityname.thal_dnacrawler>Crawler DNA</entityname.thal_dnacrawler>
  <entitydescription.thal_dnacrawler>Complete genetic sequence of the standard Europan Crawler. Can be used to develop anti-crawler technologies, or in DNA grafts for gene splicing. </entitydescription.thal_dnacrawler>
  
  <entityname.thal_planter>Hydroponics Planter Box</entityname.thal_planter>
  <entitydescription.thal_planter>An advanced planter box, designed for improved scientific measurement and botanical metrics analysis required by a botanist. Makes the difference between a hobbyist gardener and a true scientist. </entitydescription.thal_planter>
  
</infotexts>
