<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<infotexts language="English" nowhitespace="false" translatedname="English">

	<thal_timedcollar_traitormissionstartinfotext>Bomb-Voyage</thal_timedcollar_traitormissionstartinfotext>
<thal_timedcollar_traitorobjectivestartmessage1>Now that your crew has settled into the ship, you might finally have a chance to make some easy cash at long last. First thing's first:\n[traitorgoalinfos]</thal_timedcollar_traitorobjectivestartmessage1>
<thal_timedcollar_goalinfotext_1>In the [targethullname], check the cabinets. You can see the room names on a Status Monitor or an Automap.</thal_timedcollar_goalinfotext_1>
<thal_timedcollar_objectivefailmessage1>Welp. You couldn't even manage to get the collar somehow, and that's probably the end of your payment opportunity. Guess it's back to the classifieds of The Europan.</thal_timedcollar_objectivefailmessage1>
<thal_timedcollar_objectivesuccessmessage1>This is it. A weapons dealer "commissioned" you to try this on a live subject. You'd hate to have one of these strapped around your neck, and normally you'd hate to do the strapping, but you need the credits.</thal_timedcollar_objectivesuccessmessage1>
<thal_timedcollar_traitorobjectivestartmessage2>Careful not to use it on accident. Now, you'll need a diversion for everyone to occupy themselves with while you find a subject.\n[traitorgoalinfos]</thal_timedcollar_traitorobjectivestartmessage2>
<thal_timedcollar_goalinfotext_2>Sabotage the engine. It needs to be disabled to distract the attention of the others.</thal_timedcollar_goalinfotext_2>
<thal_timedcollar_objectivefailmessage2>So much for disabling the engine. Without a proper distraction, this mission has already failed.</thal_timedcollar_objectivefailmessage2>
<thal_timedcollar_objectivesuccessmessage2>Nice. That'll slow the ship down and get heads turning.</thal_timedcollar_objectivesuccessmessage2>
<thal_timedcollar_traitorobjectivestartmessage3>It's showtime! Your contractor spent hours searching for a test subject who would not be missed. Now their fate has arrived.\n[traitorgoalinfos]</thal_timedcollar_traitorobjectivestartmessage3>
<thal_timedcollar_goalinfotext_3>Knock out [targetname] somehow and strap the collar onto their head. Survive and evade detainment during the countdown, and see the collar to its detonation!</thal_timedcollar_goalinfotext_3>
<thal_timedcollar_objectivefailmessage3>Shit! Almost. Your contractor wanted the collar to kill the subject alive and nothing else. Unfortunately, you'll have to find work elsewhere, maybe in a restaurant or something, because this mission just flopped.</thal_timedcollar_objectivefailmessage3>
<thal_timedcollar_objectivesuccessmessage3>Holy shit! They're fucking dead. Obviously. Okay, don't panic, you need to get the hell out of here!</thal_timedcollar_objectivesuccessmessage3>
<thal_timedcollar_traitorobjectivestartmessage4>You need to escape before things get worse. The operative said you'd be picked up, and you can't afford to stay on this ship any longer!\n[traitorgoalinfos]</thal_timedcollar_traitorobjectivestartmessage4>
<thal_timedcollar_goalinfotext_4>Put a distance of 200 meters between yourself and the sub, whether through shuttle or underwater scooter.</thal_timedcollar_goalinfotext_4>
<thal_timedcollar_objectivefailmessage4>Oops. That did not work out the way you were expecting it to at all.</thal_timedcollar_objectivefailmessage4>
<thal_timedcollar_objectivesuccessmessage4>That should be far enough. You see what looks like a well armed military shuttle in the distance and hail to them. They slow to pick you up. Here comes the money!</thal_timedcollar_objectivesuccessmessage4>
</infotexts>
