<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<infotexts language="English" nowhitespace="false" translatedname="English">
	<!-- Loading -->
	<loadingscreentip>You are not immune to caramelldansen.</loadingscreentip>
	<loadingscreentip>You are not immune to propaganda.</loadingscreentip>
	<loadingscreentip>It is said among many that the Mime's beret makes a mime incapable of speech, but more than compensates with other supernatural abilities that can help or hurt the crew.</loadingscreentip>
	<loadingscreentip>The Honkchild's gutter dagger is designed to collect blood for sacrifices from monsters. Coincidentally, it also works on humans.</loadingscreentip>
	<loadingscreentip>Beware the Jester's tricks. Nothing is as it seems when they are onboard your vessel.</loadingscreentip>
	<loadingscreentip>Red barrels explode.</loadingscreentip>
	<loadingscreentip>If something on the ship sounds like a portal to hell is being opened, it probably is.</loadingscreentip>
	<loadingscreentip>Few have seen the horrors living in the irradiated craters in The Glow. Fewer still live to tell others.</loadingscreentip>
	<loadingscreentip>The Glow has become a notorious sector for its ability to irradiate a person such that they burn everything around them in an area of effect.</loadingscreentip>
	<loadingscreentip>Despite the massive risk present in The Glow, the rare and powerful minerals are enticing enough to tempt a brave few to don radiation suits and go mining in the irradiated sector.</loadingscreentip>
	<loadingscreentip>The requirement of oxygenite plasma packs for mining lasers either means you must be an avid ruins explorer, a wealthy portdweller, or a cunning xenobiologist in order to turn a profit.</loadingscreentip>
	<loadingscreentip>Scientists at the institute have noted an alarming social trend of previously undiscovered alien scouts leaving the confines of the ruins to patrol the surrounding areas.</loadingscreentip>
	<loadingscreentip>The riches possessed by successful coalition merchants in the central cities have allowed for a unique lavish lifestyle completely removed from that of the ordinary sailor.</loadingscreentip>
</infotexts>
