<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<infotexts language="English" nowhitespace="false" translatedname="English">

	<tutorial.clowntraining>Clown Training</tutorial.clowntraining>
	
	<thalcampaign_start.1>Welcome to Thalasssophobia's Campaign. Before you begin, you will select your background with your crew, which will affect your starting reputation.</thalcampaign_start.1>
	<thalcampaign_start.2>Decide with your crew on a background that seems fun or fitting for you.</thalcampaign_start.2>
	
	<thalcampaign_start.seeoptions>See the options.</thalcampaign_start.seeoptions>
	<thalcampaign_start.confirm>Confirm.</thalcampaign_start.confirm>
	<thalcampaign_start.back>Back to selection.</thalcampaign_start.back>
	
	<thalcampaign_start.newline>We are NEW ARRIVALS on Europa. Fate will forge a name for us.</thalcampaign_start.newline>
	<thalcampaign_newbrief>You are new arrivals on Europa. The world of Barotrauma is new and interesting. You start with no perks. No faction hates you, but no faction is fond of you. As the campaign progresses, you will be presented with the opportunity to join and leave factions as you please like any other background preset. You are your own man/woman.
	
	Choose this route to start with a clean slate, like in Vanilla Barotrauma.
	</thalcampaign_newbrief>
	
	<thalcampaign_start.corporateline>We are ELITE CORPORATE AGENTS. Our loyalty lies in COALITION INTERESTS.</thalcampaign_start.corporateline>
	<thalcampaign_corporatebrief>You work for CATPOL, a Terrorist hunting law enforcement agency. You have special access to some of the newest high-grade gear on Europa. If you stray too far from Coalition interests though, prepare to face consequences.
	
	Choose this route to play as the heavyhanded arm of the law.
	</thalcampaign_corporatebrief>
	
	<thalcampaign_start.circusline>We are A TRAVELLING CIRCUS. A carnival of chaos will swallow Europa whole.</thalcampaign_start.circusline>
	<thalcampaign_circusbrief>Clown ships go from outpost to outpost, harassing their denizens with chaotic clown antics. Clown crews will have access to ridiculous dialogue options that may result in almost spontaneous outcomes, with a large emphasis placed on RNG. Nobody is safe!
	
	This route just wants to watch the world burn.
	</thalcampaign_circusbrief>
	
	<thalcampaign_start.huskline>We are CALYX MISSIONARIES. The teachings of the husk will save humankind.</thalcampaign_start.huskline>
	<thalcampaign_huskbrief>Humanity must seek salvation from the eggs, evolving us to adapt to life on Europa. Your assignment from the high priest is to spread influence of the husk. Along the way, clergymen will aid you from the shodows to make sure no 
	
	Choose this route to take part in a transhumanism conspiracy.
	</thalcampaign_huskbrief>
	<thalcampaign_start.bluecollarline>We are A FOR-HIRE LOWLIVES. Underworld connections find us illegal work.</thalcampaign_start.bluecollarline>
	<thalcampaign_bluecollarbrief>On Europa, you're nobody until you're "in the game". As a street crew, you do it all for the marks, no questions asked. Hit job? Easy street. Narcotic smuggling? Piece of cake. You don't have a "home base"; The streets are where you were born and raised.
	
	Choose this route to experience the sprawling criminal underworld and the low life of Europa.
	</thalcampaign_bluecollarbrief>
	
	<thalcampaign_start.terroristline>We are RESISTANCE INSURGENTS. Smash the fascist state and free the moon.</thalcampaign_start.terroristline>
	<thalcampaign_terroristbrief>For years, the people of Europa have suffered under the tyrannical rule of the all-encompassing Coalition. The surveillance, the police brutality, the rampant corruption; All while Coalition fat cats live it up in luxury stations. Enough is enough.
	
	Choose this route to smash the state and stick it to the man.
	</thalcampaign_terroristbrief>

  <!-- Locations -->

  <locationname.thal_mineRadioactive>Nuclear Extraction Mine</locationname.thal_mineRadioactive>
  <locationnameformat.thal_mineRadioactive>[name]</locationnameformat.thal_mineRadioactive>
  <locationchange.thal_mineRadioactive.changeto.outpost>A new outpost has been established at [previousname], formerly a nuclear mine.</locationchange.thal_mineRadioactive.changeto.outpost>
  <locationchange.thal_mineRadioactive.changeto.military>A new military outpost has been established at [previousname], formerly a nuclear mine.</locationchange.thal_mineRadioactive.changeto.military>
  <locationchange.thal_mineRadioactive.changeto.research>A new research outpost has been established at [previousname], formerly a nuclear mine.</locationchange.thal_mineRadioactive.changeto.research>
  
  <locationname.thal_blackSite>Classified Site</locationname.thal_blackSite>
  <locationnameformat.thal_blackSite>[name]</locationnameformat.thal_blackSite>
  <locationchange.thal_blackSite.changeto.outpost>[previousname] has been converted to an outpost after a security breach jeopardized operational security.</locationchange.thal_blackSite.changeto.outpost>
  <locationchange.thal_blackSite.changeto.military>A new military outpost has been established at [previousname], formerly a classified site.</locationchange.thal_blackSite.changeto.military>
  <locationchange.thal_blackSite.changeto.research>A new research outpost has been established at [previousname], formerly a classified site.</locationchange.thal_blackSite.changeto.research>
  
</infotexts>
